Now, let's take a look at the third option, which is Amazon ECS in AWS.
There are two main container services, one is ECS, which comes in two variants,
Fargate, which is serverless, and then ECS on EC2, where you provision and easy to instance.
And this is an AWS native service.
And then you also have the managed EKS.
But the exam is mainly going to focus on Amazon ECS because it's a AWS native server.
Now, in terms of the architecture for Amazon ECS or Elastic Container service,
so it's a fully managed, highly scalable container orchestration service.
So now in terms of the management, AWS Fargate is a serverless service,
so you don't need to manage any servers.
Everything related to scaling, monitoring will be taken care of by AWS.
And then you also have the option of running the ECS on EC2 instance,
which will be a customer managed instance.
Now, in terms of the scaling, AWS Fargate can scale automatically.
And for once running on Amazon EC2, you can set up some metrics, which allows it to scale.
Now, the important thing to remember here is containers can scale in most cases much faster than EC2 instances.
Now, in terms of pricing model, again, Fargate is completely serverless,
so it's only based on pay as you use.
And in terms of when you use it, it will be based on the VCPU and memory used per second.
In case of the EC2 ECS, it will be based on the EC2 instance provision for the ECS cluster.
Okay, now the important thing, execution limit.
It is suitable for long running genii inference.
And there is no hard execution limit unlike the AWS Lambda function, which is 15 minute limit.
So, this is an important distinction in the exam to determine which service to use.
If it is less than 15 minutes, you go with AWS Lambda.
If it is more than 15 minutes, then you have the option of ECS or EC2.
Now, some of the core use cases for ECS.
First is the custom Genia orchestration.
So, if you have to write your orchestration logic, you can write the code for that and run it on ECS.
The second one is the rack pipelines.
I know we have not discussed a rack pipelines.
And there are various steps involved in the rack pipeline, chunking, vector data bases, the retrieval and so on.
And in those scenarios, and let's say you are using some open source frameworks,
such as Lang Jane or open source databases.
So, to execute those steps, you will need to write some code and that code can run on ECS.
Then microsaves based architecture and in the exam, if you hear anything related to,
then the most likely service is ECS.
It can also be used for model hosting and we saw in EC2 instance how EC2 can be used for hosting the model.
ECS also provides you option for model hosting where you can use GPU based inferences using ECS on EC2.
So, you have G5 and P4D etc that can be used.
And then finally, it can be used for any long running inference workloads.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I'll see in the next lecture.
Thank you.